<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2018 PI4 Computational Bootcamp</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on 2018 PI4 Computational Bootcamp</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Git and GitHub</title>
      <link>/2018/05/21/git-and-github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/21/git-and-github/</guid>
      <description>Version Control Following SWC Git Novice 1-6
Version control makes it possible to have ‘unlimited undo’ and histories of your documents (and some smaller datasets)
Having everything on a website like GitHub (or Bitbucket or GitLab) makes it easy to share with other people and collaborate.
If you keep all of your important programs and files somewhere in the cloud, like on box.com, dropbox, github, it makes it easier to use heterogeneous environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects Overview</title>
      <link>/2018/05/21/projects-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/21/projects-overview/</guid>
      <description>Class Projects Two groups:
Each group will have a github repository that contains code developed to answer a specific question with data from the TERRA REF project.
Here are the project topics / questions and links to their repositories.
Met data:   Create dynamic live visualizations of weather data streams from Maricopa and UIUC Energy Farm Use reanalysis data to validate data streams Extra Credit: Use PEcAn tools to gap-fill missing data  Trait and Geospatial Data   Map trait data Identify outliers Provide QA/QC of plot layout, that we are capturing expected regions of the field   Objectives Students should experience a collaborative development cycle similar to what they might encounter as a research programmer / software engineer / data scientist etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Unix Shell</title>
      <link>/2018/05/21/the-shell-and-git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2018/05/21/the-shell-and-git/</guid>
      <description>The Terminal (Unix Shell) “What is a command shell and why would I use one?”
This tutorial is based on the Software Carpentry Unix Shell) lesson. We will refer to it for background information.
Today we will learn - how the shell relates to the keyboard, the screen, the operating system, and users’ programs.&amp;quot; - when and why command-line interfaces should be used instead of graphical interfaces. - similarities and differences between a file and a directory.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading</title>
      <link>/reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/reading/</guid>
      <description>Programming Fundamentals  Wilson et al 2014 Best Practices for Scientific Computing Agile Manifesto Vincent Dresen &amp;ldquo;A successful Git branching model&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Git and GitHub&amp;rdquo; in &amp;ldquo;R packages&amp;rdquo; by Wickham.  Getting started with R  &amp;ldquo;Advanced R&amp;rdquo; by Wickham, especially:  Introduction Data Structures Subsetting Functions  R for Data Science by Wickham and Gromeland
 Tidy Data  Daniel Kaplan (2017) Teaching Stats for Data Science, The American Statistician, 72:1, 89-96, DOI: 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>Instructor: David LeBauer, Ph.D.
University of Illinois
email:dlebauer@illinois.edu
web: davidlebauer.com
Course Objectives A two week course designed to introduce graduate students from the Department of Mathematics to methods in software development, data science, and analysis. The goal is to prepare students to apply their understanding of math to solve problems in industry.
Requirements Code of Conduct All participants must read and abide by our Code of Conduct.
Preparation Please do the following before class starts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/code_of_conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code_of_conduct/</guid>
      <description>Contributor Covenant Code of Conduct Our Pledge In the interest of fostering an open and welcoming environment, we as contributors and maintainers pledge to making participation in our project and our community a harassment-free experience for everyone, regardless of age, body size, disability, ethnicity, gender identity and expression, level of experience, nationality, personal appearance, race, religion, or sexual identity and orientation.
Our Standards Examples of behavior that contributes to creating a positive environment include:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>